# PRANAV NEGANDHI

**ACTIVE PROJECTS** 

Some of the software projects I have written in my spare time. Source code and technical notes are available online at www.notadesigner.com

#### **Lib Collections**

Reinventing the data structure wheel

An experiment in unit testing

In C, because sadism is alive

### **Spreadsheet of Posts**

A spreadsheet interface to Wordpress

Improves productivity

Simplifies content entry

### **Conways Life**

Reliving CS 101 through

April 2014 • Balewadi, Pune

M: +91 98230 16832 • E: pranav@pranavnegandhi.com

### **Technologies**

ActionScript, Flex & AIR

Essential C# with WinForms and WPF

JavaScript, jQuery & Semantic markup

PHP & MySQL

Subversion

### Summary

A good web and multimedia developer with 13 years of experience in developing front-ends for the desktop and web applications. A strong grasp of software development conceptuals and several languages, including ActionScript, JavaScript and PHP. Always eager to learn new platforms.

Proven skills in designing and building software frameworks from the ground up for business applications, e-learning courseware and web-based games.

Project management activities such as client interaction, effort estimation and scheduling.

Able technical mentor.

Interested in games, data visualization tools and web-based applications.

# **Experience**

### Head of Technology, Lemon Design Pvt. Ltd.

### Vertika

Vertika is a digital display system to broadcast product information, advertisements, and training to mass audiences. The product is built using a service-oriented architecture that serves content to a rich-media frontend built using the Flex framework. The Flash platform helps leverage the benefits of a rapid development cycle and cross-platform reach.

Followed iterative processes with quick release cycles of rapid prototyping and development.

Designed and implemented a UI framework to support a variety of layouts and media types such as videos, tables, infographics (including charts, clocks and weather forecast).

arious types of widgets are implemented through decorators attached to these classes.

Vertika can be deployed as a web or a desktop application, or as a screensaver.

# Since June 2010

# **Dana Pani**This is a operations management and business intelligence product for small restaurants.

Aimed squarely at mom-and-pop run businesses, it leverages the popularity of the iOS platform to provide an immersive user experience to staff as well as customers.

This product is designed for the iPad and implemented using Adobe's AIR platform. ActionScript provides rapid development and native support for several media types and detailed typographic control.

Dana Pani is under active development.

### Team Lead, Prototype Development, Texity Systems

August 2007 to June 2010

- Part of the Design for User Experience team working for Qualcomm Enterprise Services
- Tasked with developing full-featured, high-fidelity proof-of-concept and simulation-based training tools
- Extensive interactions with the design and development teams to ensure design goals are met within technical constraints

### Sr. Web & Multimedia Developer, Fractal Ink

January 2005 to July 2007

- Developed data-driven websites, online games and multimedia presentations
- · Used common web and multimedia technologies such as PHP-MySQL, ASP-MS Access and Flash
- Introduced development practices such as coding conventions, version control, defect tracking, daily builds and functional specifications
- Initiated the development of internal tools such as attendance and time trackers
- · Also performed project management and client servicing duties for several projects

### **Project Coordinator, Cyber Backoffice**

February 2004 to December 2004

- Managed web and multimedia branding projects
- Provided technical inputs to the marketing team and translated requirements into functional documents for the developers
- Established schedules and effort estimates for projects
- Provided inputs on proposals and costs

### Lead Developer, Learnet India Ltd.

January 2001 to August 2003

- Led teams of 2-4 people in the creation of simulation-based learning projects
- Used Macromedia Director for almost all development
- Gained proficiency in object oriented development and relational databases
- Established coding conventions and code review guidelines

### **Developer, Computer Canvas**

November 1999 to December 2000

- Designed and implemented multimedia projects such as CD-ROM's, kiosks and online games, using Macromedia Director
- Also provided support as a 3D artist, using 3D Studio MAX

### **Education**

### Jai Hind College, Mumbai

1998 to 1999

• Completed F.Y.J.C, Arts from Mumbai University with 67%

### St. Mary's School, Mumbai

1996 to 1997

• Completed I.C.S.E from Delhi Board with 71%